Hello and welcome to Real easy English in this podcast we have real conversations in easy English to help you learn I'm Neil and I'm Becca you can find
A video version of this podcast with subtitles on our website, BBClearningengnglish.com. .
Hi Becca, how are you Yeah, I'm really good things, No, how about yourself.
I'm very well.
Thank you.
Your teeth are looking very bright today.
Oh Well, thank you.
I recently went to the dentist, and I had a very good clean at the dentist.
Wow Well, we are talking about the dentist today Oh, really, We are, Yes, do you like going to the dentist.
Does anyone like going to the dentist.
It can be a bit scary sometimes.
How do you feel about the.
Well I haven't been to the dentist for a long time when was the last time that you had a checkup at the dentist a checkup is when you have your
Teeth looked at by the dentist.
Well, I haven't had a checkup for a while, but the dentist said my teeth were okay,
There were no problems and I don't have any toothache.
So I don't feel like I need to go right and a toothache is when you feel pain in your teeth Have you ever had anything done to your teeth?
I have, yeah, so when I was13, I had braces put on my teeth and so braces are kind of like a wire that go across
Your teeth, and you have them done because they help to straighten your teeth My daughter had braces and they came off about a year ago, I think yes, it's funny when.
The braces come off because they the kids look different.
You're used to seeing them with Yeah, yeah, it's also really lovely to see a straight smile well with lovely straight weight teeth lots of people
Don't really like the dentist because they have to go in for a filling.
What's a filling.
A filling.
I've never had one but a filling is when a dentist will fill a hole in your teeth with.
Some kind of material and usually that whole can get bigger over time if you, for example,
Have too much sugar in your diet so I'm surprised that I've never needed a filling because I love sugar Have you ever had a filling I had a filling in a baby tooth
And we sometimes call baby teeth milk teeth as well those are the first set of teeth you have that fall out when you're still.
Very young.
But since then, I have never had a filling.
Have you ever had a really bad experience at the dentist.
Well, when I was really young, I had to have a piece of gum removed.
Gum is the pink bit that your teeth come out of, I had to have that cut away, and that was very painful, I had an injection, the injection was more painful.
Oh, it is sometimes, isn't it, Was it an injection to make you or.
Hellp you not to feel the gum coming away, so it is necessary that you have that injection or it will be really, uncomfortable.
Time now for a recap of the vocabulary that we heard in this episode starting with check up.
A check up is when you go to the dentist for the dentist to check the health of your teeth.
Yes, and we also had toothache.
Now, you would go to the dentist when you have a toothache.
An ache is a pain.
So a toothache is a pain in your teeth.
We also heard the word filling.
A filling is a piece of material which is put into a hole in your tooth.
And you get the hole in your tooth if you don't look after your teeth properly We also have braces and braces are something that you attach to your teeth to help put them in the correct
Position or straighten them.
That's it for this episode of real easyy English, but don't forget to test what you've learnedt with the free worksheet that's on our website, BBCclearningenglish.com. and we'll be back next week with another conversation in real easy English.
But for now it's goodbye, goodbye.